searchsight.com 2012-12-30

# SearchSight.com Privacy Statement

**SearchSight.com Privacy Statement**  
Posted December 20, 2007

SearchSight.com is committed to safeguarding your privacy online. Please read the following statement to understand how your personal information will be treated as you make full use of the SearchSight.com Web site. The SearchSight.com Web site is owned and operated by TJ Ventures Inc. a Louisville KY based company.

If you have any questions regarding our privacy statement, please feel free to contact us though our Comments Page.

 **Gathering of Information**

**Voluntary Submission**

SearchSight.com does not collect personally identifying information about any individual SearchSight.com web site user except when knowingly provided by such individual. For example, when a visitor comes to SearchSight.com to perform a random web search, we do not ask for nor do we collect personally identifiable information.  When a person submits a URL to be evaluated and possibly added to our search index, we require the person to include an email address to receive a confirmation email when the URL has been added to our database.  You always have the option not to provide the information we request. If you choose not to provide the information we request, you can still utilize most of the SearchSight.com Web site, but you may be unable to access certain options and services. 

Each SearchSight.com search engine listing allows for an email address to be associated with it, which is provided by the person who submits the URL for listing at the time of submission.  SearchSight.com sends a welcome email after the submitted URL has been added or updated in our search engine listings.  Occasionally SearchSight.com sends email notifications to the those who have listings in the SearchSight.com search engine to the associated email addresses.

At any time, a person who has an email address associated with one or more listings may opt to remove their email address from all listings.  This is done here.  Note:  If a URL is submitted at a future time with a removed email address, the email address will once again receive email notifications for the submitted listing.

**Cookies**

A cookie is a data file that certain Web sites write to your computer's hard drive when you visit such sites. A cookie file can contain information, such as a user identification code, that the site uses to track the pages you have visited. SearchSight.com uses cookies solely to track user traffic patterns throughout the SearchSight.com Web site. We use this data on an anonymous basis and we do not correlate this information with personal data of any user. 

Most Web site browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually change your browser settings to display a warning before accepting a cookie, or to refuse all cookies. However, if you choose to disable the receipt of cookies from our Web site, you may not be able to use certain features of the site. 

We also use third party advertisements on SearchSight.com to help support our site. Some of these advertisers may use technology such as cookies and web beacons when they advertise on our site, which will also send these advertisers (such as Google through the Google AdSense program) information including your IP address, your ISP , the browser you used to visit our site, and various browser options you may have installed on your web browser. This is generally used for geotargeting purposes or showing certain ads based on specific sites visited.

**Browser Level Information**

SearchSight.com Web servers automatically collect information about a site user's IP address, browser type and referrer by reading this information from the user's browser (information provided by every user's browser). This information is collected in a database and used in an aggregated, anonymous manner in our internal analysis of traffic patterns within our Web site. This information is automatically logged by most Web sites. 

**Use of Information**

Our primary goal in collecting user information is to enhance your experience on our Web site. We achieve this goal by, among other things, providing interactive communications such as our welcome email, and developing future products and services based on your interests. To develop content targeted to your interests, we use aggregated user information to determine which areas of our Web site users prefer based upon traffic to those areas. We do not track what individual users read, but instead how well each page or content area performs overall. 

SearchSight.com derives the majority of its revenue from advertising. In order to attract and retain advertisers we may use the aggregated, anonymous information that we gather to describe our services to partners and to assist our advertisers and sponsors to better understand our audience. We do not disclose personally identifying information about our users to these parties. 

SearchSight.com may also disclose information about our users when we believe, in good faith, that the disclosure is required by law. 

When you are on an area of SearchSight.com and are asked for personal information, you are sharing that information with SearchSight.com as well as business partners and vendors providing hosting and other services for SearchSight.com. If you do not want your information to be shared, you can choose not to allow the transfer of your information by not using that particular service. These parties, as well as advertisers who contract directly with a third-party service to serve their advertisements, may set their own cookies. 

In addition, any personally identifiable information provided by our users as part of an advertiser promotion online may be provided directly to advertisers. 

Please be aware that SearchSight.com partners, sponsors, advertisers or Web sites that have links on our site may collect personally identifiable information about you. The information practices of those parties and Web sites linked to SearchSight.com are not covered by this privacy statement. SearchSight.com users should also be aware that, when you voluntarily disclose personal information in chat areas or bulletin boards, that information may be collected by others and may result in unsolicited messages from others. 

Kids under 13: Do not send any information about yourself to us, including information such as your name, address, or e-mail address. We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under 13. In the event that we learn we have collected any personal information from a child under the age of 13 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information from our database as quickly as possible. 

**E-Mail**

SearchSight.com respects the privacy of its users and shall not disclose, distribute or rent its e-mail subscriber newsletter list to any third party, unless we feel such disclosure shall be beneficial to our users.  Users with listings in the SearchSight.com database may change the email associated with their listing at any time by following the procedure outlined in our Webmaster Frequently Asked Questions. 

**How to Contact Us**

If you have any questions regarding our privacy statement, please feel free to contact us though our Comments Page.

This statement may change from time to time, so please check back periodically. 

© 2006 - 2012 SearchSight.com Inc. All Rights Reserved. 

**Definitions:**

**IP address:** Every computer connected to the Internet has a numeric address called an “IP address." This may or may not correspond uniquely to a particular computer. In some cases, IP addresses can be resolved to domain names, which may indicate a site visitor's Internet service provider, employer, university, etc. As part of its database analysis SearchSight.com resolves IP addresses to domain names. 

**Browser type:** A user’s browser is a software program running on a computer that allows users to access documents on the World Wide Web. Browsers can be either text or graphic. They read HTML coded pages that reside on a server and interpret the coding into what the user sees as Web pages. Netscape Navigator and Microsoft Internet Explorer are examples of Web browsers. Browser type typically discloses hardware platform, operating system, and browser software and version.

**Referrer:** The referrer is the URI of the Internet resource or page that causes a browser to request a page or image from SearchSight.com servers.

**Advertiser:** Someone who has submitted a URL or has had their URL submitted to SearchSight.com.  SearchSight.com offers some advertiser services for free, and some for a fee.
